Derek A. Shain

Software Developer

208-606-2581, derek0anthony@gmail.com, https://github.com/DerekShain, www.linkedin.com/in/derekshain

Profile:

A software developer with the ability to learn new technologies in a fast-paced environment. Experienced in front and back-end development. Efficient and effective lead/supervisor able to produce under pressure as proven over in five years of military service and in the civilian workforce. Commended for tactful, professional, and efficient communication skills at all levels of management. Seeking an opportunity in the Software Development world to expand my knowledge and growth and help develop the future.

Skills:

- C#/.Net
 JavaScript
 Node.js
 Mongoose
 Agile/Scrum
- MySQL
 Vue.js
 MongoDB
 HTML/SCSS
 Figma

Experience:

Software Development Student, CodeWorks

08/2021-

- 11/2021
 - Learned Javascript ES6, C#, dotNet, NodeJs, SQL, MySQL, Vue, Agile/Scrum processes, Backend and front-end development, and the value of integrating security
 - Utilized scrum processes to build multiple applications efficiently and effectively
 - Multiple application development with MVC, multiple API's, custom design using Figma, security with Auth0, online storage with Google Firebase, and database hosting with MongoDB

Applications:

Myst

- Gaming Social Media site with current news and live streams
- Developer, UI/UX design
- Vue, MySQL, JS, SCSS

Sprintr

- Scrum Management
- Developer, UI/UX design
- Vue, Node.Js, JS, MongoDB

Product Flow Member, Best Buy

10/2020- Current

- Assisted customers with questions on upcoming new products and services to include drone laws and regulations and Windows 11 deployment.
- Receive and Ship items as needed, ensure floor has appropriate level of stock items
- Assisted with processing online orders, maintained knowledge of hundreds of products to stay up to date on current trends.

Receiving/Manifest Lead - Supply Chain, CTI Foods

12/2019-10/2020

- Oversee receiving and other warehouse processes and lead 8 personnel to make sure work meets quality standards and is performed according to established procedures.
- Assist with the development, revision and enforcement of inventory management and procedures including record keeping, work instructions, ISO procedures, and other standard operational and work practices as necessary.
- Implemented a new way to track incoming and current inventory while developing a manifesting position through months of research utilizing Tableau and other systems.
- Continue to grow lean knowledge and use the tools to identify and assist with continuous improvement.

- Cultivate relationships with new customers to achieve sales objectives and provide insight into new products, features, and
 options.
- Researched new automotive releases to maintain knowledge of new products and trends.

Management Trainee, Warehouse, J.R. Simplot Company

02/2018-10/2018

- Cover for shift supervisors and transportation coordinators as needed.
- Ensure accurate inventory control by monitoring and using various best practices inventory techniques to ensure custody of
 products received from Idaho production and other facilities are properly taken care of.
- Performs related duties such as transmitting and tracking information via computer concerning inventory, shipping/receiving, timekeeping, productivity, and storage availability.
- Responsible for supporting, managing, or implementing Food Safety and Product Quality standards as well as USDA/FDA
 regulations and policies in moving temperature-controlled products through the supply chain utilizing best practices.
- Ensured safety and security protocols are followed by all personnel
- Developed an SOP and safety plan for loading Airbags onto Rail cars

Process Operator A2, J.R. Simplot Company

06/2014-02/2018

- Ensuring product quality and production levels are achieved and sustained for the processing equipment
- Providing electronic and mechanical maintenance, operation, sanitation, troubleshooting and repair of all processing equipment.
- Ensured USDA, OSHA, and EPA regulations were being followed.

Logistics Specialist 3rd Class (Expeditionary Warfare Specialist), United States Navy Reserve

05/2011-05/2015

- Ordered, stocked, issued repair parts, clothing, and general supplies
- Maintained Inventory databases for material stocked
- Performed duties associated with hazardous material control and management
- Specialty Training includes Stevedore (shipboard cargo handler) and Expeditionary Warfare Specialist (extensively detailed training certifying I can operate, navigate, and coordinate logistical support and combat operations in various combat environments).

Tactical Aircraft Maintenance Journeyman, United States Air Force

06/2008-10/2010

- Used Technical Data to Diagnose and Solve Maintenance Problems
- Removed and installed aircraft components and systems
- Performed aircraft jacking, lifting, and towing operations
- Inspected Aircraft Structures, Systems, and Components
- Interpreted inspection findings and determined adequacy of Corrective Actions
- Reviewed Maintenance Forms, Aircraft Records, automated maintenance data systems and historical reports to ensure complete documentation

Education:

Codeworks (2021)

-Full stack Software Development

Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University (2017)

United States Military Education (2015)

- -Navy War College
- -Community College of the Airforce